If you were to ask chat GPD to create a
presentation based on the contents of
this blog post, it will be able to read
the blog post and then write Python code
for the presentation. Now, here's the
final outcome. The content is there, but
the formatting is hit and miss. Cloud
Opus, on the other hand, does a much
better job. However, the formatting is
still not consistent and there are some
very weird formatting issues and if you
were to change a single slide, the agent
will redo the whole tech for you in a
completely different format. That's why
dedicated tools like gumup comes into
play. You can create beautiful
consistent
presentations and slide text using their
AI agent. And now they just introduced
their GMA API where you can create
presentations on your contents at scale.
So for example, here is a web interface
that I created that can generate the
same slides in multiple different
languages. More on this later in the
video. And this is powered by GMA API.
You can also use GMA API with tools like
Zapier or Make to completely automate
your presentation creation at bulk. GMA
is also the kind sponsor of today's
video. Okay, so let me first walk you
through the platform and then I'll show
you how to use the API for bulk creation
of presentations and web pages. They
recently had GMA 3 release with which
they are introducing GMA agent. So for
example, if you click on create new, you
can use the agent to help you create
powerful presentations. You have three
different options. First is you provide
the outline or the content of your
presentation. Next, you can provide a
single prompt. The agent will do
research for you and then create
presentations based on that. And the
third one is either to import files or
direct the agent towards URL. So for
this quick example, we're going to be
using this blog post writing effective
tools for agents with agents. So I'm
going to just copy the URL. I want a
presentation based on the contents of
this web page for my work and this
YouTube channel. I create a lot of
presentations which are grounded in the
material that I'm providing. So a tool
like GMA is going to be extremely
helpful for those use cases. Now here we
can just provide the URL. So here's the
link. Also you can upload existing
PowerPoint presentations, docs, PDF
files or you can import from Google
Drive or Google Docs which is extremely
helpful. Okay, so we're going to just
import this. Now here it asks us whether
you want to create a presentation,
webpage document or a post for social
media. I'm going to click on
presentation then click continue. So you
can see that it was able to parse the
whole document. It's even keeping all
the images. And now you have a few
options here. You can control the amount
of text. We're going to just keep it to
concise. You also have the ability to
select different visual themes. So I'm
going to just select this. And for
images, you can have AI generated images
or it can do web search. I just like to
have illustrations there. So I'm going
to select that. Now you can also provide
additional
context to the agent. So here I'm going
to tell it to use images and plots from
the blog post itself which is pretty
awesome because if you use chart GPT or
even entropic opus for they usually are
not able to parse images correctly. So
here now it's creating the contents for
us based on the material that we
provided. I think by default it
generates 10 slides but you can control
that and ask it to create more. Now you
can already see that it added an image
from the blog post into the
presentation. Now it is also copying
images directly when it's talking about
performance which is pretty awesome.
Okay. So the first iteration of the
presentation is ready and you can here
check whether it's actually grounded in
the material that you provided or not.
In my case, it does seem to be grounded
in the information that is in the blog
post itself. Now, let's use the agent to
make some changes. So, for example, on
this specific
slide, I want to change this into a
diagram or a workflow. Okay. So, here
I'm going to just use WordB. Can you
create a flowchart which shows the
difference between
traditional software engineering tools
and agentic tools based on the
information that was provided in the
blog post. Okay. So I'm happy with this.
We're going to send in. So on the
sidebar you can see that the agent is
creating another slide for us that
introduced the workflow. So in the blog
post they talk about deterministic
software where you have your input
deterministic function and predicted
output. When it comes to agentic tools
the agent is able to make decisions
which are non-deterministic and it's
able to capture that. Now one thing
which you'll notice is that it's keeping
the theme consistent which is pretty
awesome. So you can really create
targeted edits with the help of this
agent without affecting the overall
theme of your slide deck. Also, just
like software engineering, it does
version control. So here's the original
version of the slide deck. And then this
is the modified version, which is a
pretty neat feature. Okay, one more
thing. You can change the language of
the entire slide deck or a single slide.
So let's say we're going to use the same
tool. Can you change the language to
Arabic for this specific slide? Okay. So
I'm happy with the transcription.
Going to send that in again. The agent
is going to start looking at that slide
and hopefully we'll make edits to only
this one slide. And yes. Okay. So the
rest of the presentation
is in English and it's able to make
edits to that one specific slide. Now
think of this. If you create a slide in
one language, then you can use the agent
to just recreate multiple different
versions of the same slide deck in
multiple different languages or for
different regions, which is I think a
crazy productivity
unlocker. Next, I'm going to show you
how to create presentations using the
API, which is going to be of interest to
developers out there. Here's a simple
web app that I created where you can
provide the GMA API key along with a
text prompt. This can be as simple as
providing a web link the way we have
been doing. Then you can select multiple
different languages if you want. And you
also have the option to either create an
expanded version, summarized version, or
keep the original content. And you can
either create a presentation or a
document. And based on that, I created
this web app. Link to this is going to
be in the video description. Now, in
order to use the API, you need to be on
the pro plan. You can get started for
free, but this is going to be extremely
helpful for organizations and teams that
are creating a lot of presentations and
documents. So, if you're on the pro
plan, go to settings and members. And
here you're going to see API keys. You
can create a new API key. Just copy that
API key. And then, if you're running my
web app, you can just paste the API key
here. Now, in this case, we're going to
use the same text prompt. I can select
multiple different languages, but let's
keep it to English only. Then, let's
click generate and let's hit generate.
Okay. So right now it's processing. This
is going to take a couple of minutes.
Now for this specific web app, if you
select multiple different languages, it
will be just making multiple different
calls to the API endpoint. The content
may vary between different presentations
because these are independent calls.
Okay. So the presentation actually is
going to show up here. You can click on
it and then you can use the same agent
as before to make any adjustments that
you want which is pretty neat. So with
this API I think it's going to be a very
powerful tool for developers who want to
create documentations and presentations
in bulk. So do check them out. I think
it's going to be an extremely helpful
tool and I can actually see myself using
it a lot. Anyways, do let me know what
you think and if you find this video
useful, do like and subscribe. Anyways,
I hope you found this video useful.
Thanks for watching and as always, see
you in the next one.